One of the exciting things about a large language model is you could use it to
关于大语言模型的一个令人兴奋的事情，是你可以用它来
build a custom chatbot with only a modest amount of effort
构建一个自定义的聊天机器人，只需花费少量的精力
ChatGPT, the web interface is a way for you to have a conversational interface
ChatGPT的Web界面能让你通过一个大语言模型
a conversation via a large language model
进行对话
But one of the cool things is you can also use
但其中一个很酷的事情是你也可以使用
a large language model to build your custom chatbot
一个大语言模型来建立你的自定义聊天机器人
to maybe play the role of an AI customer service agent or
也许可以扮演一个AI客户服务代理或
an AI order taker for restaurants
餐馆的AI接单员
And in this video, you learn how to do that for yourself
在这段视频中，你将学习如何做这件事
I'm going to describe the components of
我将描述以下内容
the OpenAI chat completions format in more detail
我将更详细地描述OpenAI的聊天补全格式
and then you're going to build a chatbot yourself
然后你将自己建立一个聊天机器人
So let's get into it
所以让我们开始吧
So first, we'll set up the OpenAI Python package as usual
首先，我们将像往常一样设置OpenAI Python包
So chat models like ChatGPT are actually trained to take a series of
因此，像ChatGPT这样的聊天模型实际上是被训练成以一系列的信息作为输入
messages as input and return a model generated message as output
并返回模型生成的信息作为输出
And so although the chat format is designed to
因此，尽管聊天格式的设计是为了
make multi-turn conversations like this easy
使得像这样的多轮对话变得容易
we've kind of seen through the previous videos that it's also just as
我们在之前的视频中已经看到
useful for single-turn tasks without any conversation
它也适用于没有对话的单个任务
And so next, we're going to kind of define two helper functions
所以接下来，我们要定义两个辅助函数
So this is the one that we've been using throughout all the videos
就是我们在所有视频中一直在使用的一个
and it's the get_completion function
get_completion函数
But if you kind of look at it
但是，如果你看一下它
we give a prompt, but then kind of inside the function
我们给出了一个提示，但是在这个函数里面
what we're actually doing is putting this prompt into what looks
我们实际上在做的是把这个提示放到一个
what looks like some kind of user message
看起来像某种用户信息
And this is because the ChatGPT model is a chat model
这是因为ChatGPT模型是一个聊天模型
which means it's trained to take a series of messages as input
这意味着它被训练成以一系列信息作为输入
and then return model generated messages output
然后返回模型生成的信息输出
So the user message is kind of
所以用户信息是一种输入
the input and then the assistant message is the output
然后助理的信息是输出
So in this video
所以在这个视频中
we're going to actually use a different helper function
我们将使用一个不同的辅助函数
And instead of kind of putting
而不是把
a single prompt as input and getting a single completion
单一提示作为输入并获得单一结果
we're going to pass in a list of messages
我们将传入一个信息列表
And these messages can be kind of from a variety of different roles
这些信息可以来自各种不同的角色
So I'll describe those
所以我将描述这些
So here's an example of a list of messages
这里有一个消息列表的例子
And so the first message is
第一条信息是
a system message which kind of gives an overall instruction
一个系统消息，它给出了一个总体指令
And then after this message
然后在这个消息之后
we have kind of turns between the user and the assistant
我们在用户和助理之间有几轮对话
And this is kind of continue to go on
而且这种对话通常会继续下去
And if you've ever used ChatGPT, the web interface
如果你曾经使用过ChatGPT的Web界面
then your messages are the user messages
那么你输入的信息就是用户信息
and then ChatGPT's messages are the assistant messages
然后ChatGPT的信息是助理的信息
So the system message helps to kind of
因此，系统信息有助于在某种程度上
set the behavior and persona of the assistant
设定助理的行为和角色
and it acts as kind of a high-level instruction for the conversation
它就像对话的高级指令一样
So you can kind of think of it as whispering in
所以你可以把它看成是
the assistant's ear and kind of guiding
在助理的耳边说的话，并引导
its responses without the user being aware of the system message
它的反应，而用户并不知道系统的信息
So as the user
因此，作为用户
if you've ever used ChatGPT
如果你曾经使用过ChatGPT
you probably don't know what's in ChatGPT's system message
你可能不知道ChatGPT的系统消息里有什么
The benefit of the system message is that it provides you
系统消息的好处是
the developer, with a way to kind of frame
它为开发者提供了一种方法来框定会话
the conversation without making
而不是让请求本身
the request itself part of the conversation
成为对话的一部分
So you can kind of guide the assistant and kind of whisper in
这样，你就可以在不让用户察觉的情况下引导助理
its ear and guide its responses without making the user aware
并指导其回复
So now let's try to use these messages in a conversation
所以现在让我们试着在对话中使用这些信息
So we'll use our new helper function to get
所以我们将使用我们的新助理函数
the completion from the messages
来补全消息内容
and we're also using a higher temperature
而且我们也在使用更高的temperature
So the system message says
所以系统消息说
you are an assistant that speaks like Shakespeare
你是一个说话像莎士比亚的助理
So this is us kind of
所以这是我们在向助理描述
describing to the assistant how it should behave
向助理描述它应该如何表现
and then the first user message is, tell me a joke
然后第一个用户信息是，告诉我一个笑话
The next is, why did the chicken cross the road?
接下来是，鸡为什么要过马路？
Then the final user message is, I don't know
然后最后的用户信息是，我不知道
So if we run this
所以，如果我们运行这个
the response is to get to the other side. Let's try again
响应是"去到另一边"。让我们再试一次
To get to the other side
"要到另一边去"
fair sir or madam
公平的先生或女士
it is an old and classic that never fails
这是一个古老而经典的方法，永远不会失败
So that's our Shakespearean response
所以这就是我们的莎士比亚式响应
Let's actually try one more thing because I want to make
让我们再试一次
it even clearer that this is the assistant message
因为我想让它更清楚，这是助理的信息
So here let's just go and print the entire message response
所以在这里，让我们去打印整个消息的回应
So just to make this even clearer
所以只是为了让这个更清楚
this response is an assistant message
这个响应是一个助理信息
So the role is assistant and then the content is the message itself
所以角色是助理，然后内容是消息本身
So that's what's happening in this helper function
所以这就是在这个辅助函数中发生的事情
We're just passing out the content of the message
我们只是传出了消息的内容
So now let's do another example
所以现在让我们再做一个例子
So here our messages are
这里我们的消息是
the system message is you're a friendly chatbot
系统信息是你是一个友好的聊天机器人
and the first user message is
而第一个用户信息是
hi, my name is Isa
嗨，我的名字是Isa
We want to get the first user message
我们想获得第一个用户的信息
So let's execute this
所以让我们执行这个
the first assistant message
第一条助理信息
So the first message is
因此，第一条信息是
hello Isa, it's nice to meet you
你好，Isa，很高兴见到你
How can I assist you today?
我今天有什么可以帮助你的吗？
Now let's try another example
现在让我们试试另一个例子
So here our messages are system message
所以这里我们的信息是系统信息
you're a friendly chatbot
你是一个友好的聊天机器人
and the first user message is
和第一个用户信息是
yes, can you remind me what is my name?
是的，你能提醒我我的名字是什么吗？
Let's get the response
让我们得到回应
As you can see
正如你所看到的
the model doesn't actually know my name
该模型实际上并不知道我的名字
So each conversation with a language model is a standalone interaction
因此，与语言模型的每一次对话都是一个独立的互动
which means that you must provide all relevant messages
这意味着，你必须提供所有相关的信息
for the model to draw from in the current conversation
供模型在当前对话中使用
If you want the model to draw from or
如果你想让模型从或中汲取
quote unquote, remember earlier parts of a conversation
引述，记住一个对话的早期部分
you must provide the earlier exchanges in the input to the model
你必须在模型的输入中提供早期的对话交互内容
So we'll refer to this as context
我们也把这称为上下文
So let's try this
所以，让我们来试试这个
So now we've given the context that the model needs
所以现在我们已经给出了模型需要的上下文
which is my name in the previous messages
这是我在以前的信息中的名字
and we'll ask the same question
我们将问同样的问题
So we'll ask what my name is
所以我们会问我的名字是什么
and the model is able to respond because it has all of the context it
模型能够作出反应，因为它有所有的上下文
needs in this list of messages that we input to it
在我们输入的消息列表中需要它
So now you're going to build your own chatbot
所以现在你要建立你自己的聊天机器人
This chatbot is going to be called orderbot
这个聊天机器人将被称为orderbot（点餐机器人）
and we're going to automate the collection of
我们将自动收集
user prompts and assistant responses in order to build this orderbot
我们将自动收集用户的提示和助理的回应，以建立这个订单机器人
It's going to take orders at a pizza restaurant
它将在一家披萨店接受订单
So first, we're going to define this helper function
所以首先，我们要定义这个助理函数
What this is doing is it's going to collect
这个函数要做的是收集
our user messages so we can avoid typing them in by hand in the way that we did above
我们的用户信息，这样我们就可以避免像上面那样用手输入信息了
This is going to collect prompts from a user interface that we'll build below
这将从我们下面建立的用户界面上收集提示信息
and then append it to a list called context
然后将其追加到一个叫做"上下文"的列表中
and then it will call the model with that context every time
然后它每次都会用这个上下文调用模型
The model response is then also added to the context
然后模型的响应也会被添加到上下文中
So the model message is added to the context
所以模型的信息被添加到上下文中
the user message is added to the context
用户信息被添加到上下文中
so on, so it just grows longer and longer
以此类推，它只会越来越长
This way, the model has the information it needs to determine what to do next
这样一来，模型就有了它所需要的信息来决定下一步该做什么
So now we'll set up and run this UI to display the orderbot
现在我们将设置并运行这个用户界面来显示订单机器人
So here's the context
所以这里是上下文
and it contains the system message that contains the menu
并且它包含了包含菜单的系统信息
Note that every time we call the language model
请注意，每次我们调用语言模型的时候
we're going to use the same context and the context is building up over time
我们都会使用相同的上下文，而且这个上下文是随着时间的推移而建立的
Then let's execute this
然后让我们来执行这个
I'm going to say, hi
我要说，你好
I would like to order a pizza
我想订购一个比萨饼
The assistant says, great
助理说，太好了
what pizza would you like to order?
你想点什么比萨饼？
We have pepperoni, cheese, and eggplant pizza
我们有意大利香肠、奶酪和茄子比萨
How much are they?
多少钱？
Great. Okay, we have the prices
很好。好的，我们得到了价格
I think I'm feeling a medium eggplant pizza. So as you can imagine
我想我觉得是中号茄子比萨。所以你可以想象
we could continue this conversation
我们可以继续这个对话
Let's look at what we've put in the system message
让我们看看我们在系统信息中放了什么
So you are orderbot
所以你是orderbot
an automated service to collect orders for a pizza restaurant
为一家比萨店收集订单的自动化服务
You first greet the customer
你首先要问候顾客
then collect the order and then ask if it's a pickup or delivery
然后收集订单，再问是自取还是配送
You wait to collect the entire order
你等待收集整个订单
then summarize it and check for a final time
然后总结一下，最后进行检查
if the customer wants to add anything else
如果顾客还想添加其他东西
If it's a delivery, you can ask for an address
如果是送货，你可以要求提供地址
Finally, you collect the payment
最后，你拿到付款
Make sure to clarify all options, extras
确保清晰描述所有选项、附加服务、额外费用
and sizes to uniquely identify the item from the menu
和尺寸，以便从菜单上精确识别该项目
You respond in a short
你需要以简短的
very conversational, friendly style
健谈的、友好的风格来回答
The menu includes, and then here we have the menu
菜单包括，然后在这里我们有菜单
So let's go back to our conversation
所以让我们回到我们的对话
And let's see if the assistant kind of has been following the instructions
让我们看看助理是否一直在遵循指示
Okay, great. The assistant asks if we want any toppings
好的，很好。助理问我们是否需要任何配料
which we kind of specified in the system message
我们在系统信息中指定了这一点
So I think we want no extra toppings
所以我想我们不需要额外的配料
Sure thing. Is there anything else we'd like to order?
当然可以。还有什么我们想点的吗？
Hmm. Let's get some water
嗯。让我们来点水
Actually, fries
事实上，薯条
Small or large?
小的还是大的？
And this is great because we kind of
这很好，因为我们在系统信息中
ask the assistant in the system message to kind of clarify extras and sides
要求助理在系统信息中说明额外的东西和配菜
And so you get the idea and please feel free to play with this yourself
这样你就明白了，你可以随意试玩一下这个过程
You can pause the video and just go ahead and run this in your own notebook on the left
可以暂停视频，在左边的Notebook上运行这个
And so now we can ask the model to create a JSON summary
现在我们可以要求该模型创建一个JSON摘要
that we could send to the order system based on the conversation
我们可以在对话的基础上发送至订单系统
So we're now appending another system message
所以，我们现在要附加另一个系统消息
which is an instruction
这是一个指令
And we're saying create a JSON summary of the previous food order
我们在说创建一个关于之前食品订单的JSON摘要
Itemize the price for each item
逐项列出每一项的价格
The fields should be one pizza, include side
字段应该是一个比萨饼，包括配菜
two lists of toppings, three lists of drinks
两张配料表，三张饮料表
and four lists of sides
和四份配菜清单
And finally, the total price
最后是总价格
And you could also use a user message here
你也可以在这里使用一个用户信息
This does not have to be a system message
这不一定是一个系统消息
So let's execute this
所以让我们来执行这个
And notice in this case, we're using a lower temperature
注意在这种情况下，我们需要使用更低的temperature
because for these kinds of tasks
因为对于这些类型的任务
we want the output to be fairly predictable
我们希望输出是相当可预测的
For a conversational agent, you might want to use a higher temperature
对于一个对话式的代理，你可能想使用更高的temperature
However, in this case, I would maybe use a lower temperature as well
然而，在这种情况下，我可能也会使用一个较低的temperature
because for a customer assistant chatbot
因为对于一个客户助理聊天机器人来说
you might want the output to be a bit more predictable as well
你可能想让输出更可预测一些
And so here we have the summary of our order
因此，在这里我们有我们的订单摘要
And so we could submit this to the order system if we wanted to
如果我们想的话，我们可以把这个提交给订单系统
So there we have it
这就是我们需要的
You've built your very own order chatbot
你已经建立了你自己的订单聊天机器人
Feel free to kind of customize it yourself
你可以自由地定制它
and play around with the system message
试玩一下系统信息
and kind of change the behavior of the chatbot
并改变聊天机器人的行为
and get it to act as different personas with different knowledge
让它作为具有不同知识的不同角色行事